杰森:咦,醒醒,醒醒,我早上有起来做早餐,
Jason: Make breakfast, make coffee, wake up!Better wake up first.Oh.
煮咖啡吗?我真的做过早餐吗?我真的煮了咖啡吗?没错,
I made breakfast?Did I make coffee?I did.
这些都是我做的.让我想想,让我想想,我今天早上还做过什么事情了?
Wonder what else I've done this morning?
迈克:早上好,爸爸.
Mike: Hey!Good morning, Dad.
迈克:恩.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:早上好,迈克.你起来啦.
Jason: Hey, Mike, you're up.
杰森:我睡过头了,已经到中午了.
Jason: I've over-slept, it must be noon.
迈克:没呢,老爸,现在才早上6点半.
Mike: Oh no, Dad, it's only six thirty.
杰森:啊,真是太不可思议了,
Jason: Oh, well that's terrific, Mike;
迈克;开学的第一天,
your very first day of the new semester, and you decide to stay out all night.
你居然就跑去外面鬼混.真让人痛心.
That's very smart.
迈克:爸爸,我没有出去鬼混!
Mike: Dad, I did not stay out all night!
杰森:现在才6点半,你是刚从外面回来吧!
Jason: Well, I call Six thirty am, staying out all night!
迈克:爸,我才不是刚进门呢.你看,你看...
Mike: Dad, I did not just get in.Look...look...I...
今天早上睡不着,很早就醒了,所以,我就起来准备早餐.
I woke up early and I made breakfast.
杰森:迈克,快说,那女孩是谁?
Jason: Who's the girl, Mike?
迈克:爸,这里有女孩子吗?
Mike: Dad, do you see a girl in here?
杰森:我是问在你房间里的,
Jason: No!I'm talking about the girl in your apartment,
让你准备早餐的女孩子.
that you got up early to make breakfast for.
迈克:爸,因为开学第一天要上的课让我兴奋不已,所以,我才起来的这么早的.
Mike: Dad, I got up early because I'm excited about my first day of class.
杰森:哦?啊哈!有什么特别的课程吗?
Jason: Oh?Aha!So, any class in particular.
迈克:当然,爸爸!今天有表演简介课,
Mike: Yeah, Dad!Look, Introduction to Acting.
这门课不仅仅只是学那些开萝尔赖以生存的书本,试卷,
I mean, Dad this class is not just a bunch of books and papers and other
和其他毫无用处的垃圾.学这门课,我们要做的只是表演.
pointless, useless garbage that Carol lives for.I mean, all that we do is act.
麦琪:杰森,你一大早就在对谁"啊哈"呀?
Maggie: Jason, who are you "aha-ing" to at this time in the morning?
杰森:哦,迈克早早的起来为我们准备了早餐,
Jason: Well, Mike got up early, he made breakfast,
据说是因为今天要上的课让他兴奋不已.
and he's excited about a class.
麦琪:女孩在哪里?
Maggie: Where is she?
迈克:妈,别这样!
Mike: Mom, come on!
麦琪:啊哈!那你的表演课怎么样?
Maggie: Aha!So, what about this acting class?
开萝尔:啊哈!
Carol: Aha!
迈克:你们这是什么态度嘛?
Mike: What is it with you people?
说的好象我从来没有关心过学习似的!
You act like I have never cared about school in my life!
马迹:啊哈.
Maggie: Aha.
迈克:妈妈,事实上我对很多课程都很重视的.
Mike: Mom, I have been excited about school, dozens of times.
开萝尔:说一个来听听!
Carol: Name one!
杰森:开萝尔,和你没关系.迈克,说一个来听听!
Jason: Carol, this doesn't concern you.Name one!
迈克:比如说,人体摄影.
Mike: Alright, Nude Photography.
还有今天让我能这么早起床的表演课,不过到等到中午才上.
Now I was up early for that one, and that class didn't start till noon.
杰森:原来如此,他要上裸体表演课!
Jason: That's it, he's taking a nude acting class!
本:迈克要上裸体表演课?
Ben: Mike's in a nude acting class?
迈克:对,本,
Mike: Yeah, yeah Benny, I'm in a nude acting class!
你说的没错,我是要上裸体表演课!我的房间里还藏着一个女孩呢,
And I've got a girl hidden up in my room,
对了,在柜台下还藏着另外一个,我准备的早餐,
plus a spare one stashed under the counter, and I've made breakfast;
都给你吧,尽管吃!
they're all yours, take your pick!
迈克:嘿嘿,我提前到了,我提前好久到学校了!为什么不呢?我也可以提前到学校的.现在颁发最佳男演员奖---迈克西维尔!!迈克!迈克!迈克!迈克!,哦,你好,啊,我刚才只是在...呃...在测试这里的音响效果...喂,迈克,迈克.听上去还不错.我是迈克西维尔.
Mike: I'm early.I'm very early.Heck, why not?I can do this.And now accepting the best actor award for Mike Seaver is...Mike Seaver!!Mike!Mike!Mike!Mike!Oh, hi, ah, I was just...err...testing out the acoustics here...Mike, Mike.Sounds good to me.Mike Seaver.
托尼:托尼迪斯皮欧.
Tony: Tony Dissipio.
迈克∶你为这节课做好准备了?
Mike: So, you ready for this class?
托尼:是的.我可以告诉你真相--我平生都没有来过这么早,除了去年的裸体摄影课.
Tony: Oh, I sure am.I'll tell you the truth- I've never been early for a class in my whole life, except that nude photography course last year.
迈克∶我们...但是,我在人体摄影1班上好像没见过你呀.
Mike: We...I don't remember you in Nude Photography 1.
托尼∶我在二班.等等,
Tony: I was in two.
在我开始和你做朋友前,
Hey, listen, wait, before I get to like you- your not one of these big
我得问问清楚,
deal actors, with a list of credits from here to Broadway,
你是腰缠万贯的百老汇大明星,还是只是这个班上的一个穷小子?
just slumming in this class?
迈克∶哦,不,不,不,
Mike: Oh, no...no, no, I'm...err...I've only done a couple of things...
我只是...我只做过几件事而已...不过不是在百老汇.
err...off Broadway.
托尼:不在百老汇?我都是在夏季聚集演出.
Tony: Off Broadway?All I got is a couple of seasons of summer stock.
迈克∶哦哦,这里有夏季聚集可以演呀.那你们两个应该认识啦.你好,我叫迈克西维尔.
Mike: Wow, now there's some summer stock.So, I guess you two know each other.Hi, my name is Mike Seaver.
凯∶我是凯麦克旦尼尔.认识你很高兴,迈克.
Kay: Kay McDonnell.Nice to meet you, Mike.
迈克∶我也是.当然,大部分还是对托尼的.恩,你们俩有没有听说过这个老师怎么样?
Mike: The pleasure's all mine.OK, it's mostly Tony's.So...err...what do you guys hear about this teacher?
凯∶我听说索恩教授是斯特拉斯堡法的大师.
Kay: Well, I understand that Professor Thorn is a master of the Strasbourg method.
迈克∶嘿嘿,了解一下总是好的.
Mike: Oh hey, that's good to know.
我是说,如果老师让我们其中任何一个难堪的话,我们可以掩护一下.
I mean, if any one of us chokes on our gum, we got it covered.
教授∶你为什么认为你们会被惩罚吗?你说!
Professor: Now, why did you believe that your about to be scalded?You!
迈克∶哦,因为,呃,因为我以前的老师就这样对我的.
Mike: Oh, because...err...Well, 'cause I've had teachers do that to me.
教授∶还有你!
Professor: And you!
托尼∶因为你在演戏.
Tony: Because you were acting.
教授:很好.大家早上好!
Professor: Precisely.Good morning everyone!
我是彼得教授,欢迎来到102戏剧班.
My name is Professor Peter Thorn, and welcome to Drama 102.
这是你们的第一节课,是入门课.
You've just had your first lesson, in how to make an entrance.
你们已经听了我的笑话,很好.
Come on, you're laughing at my jokes already, very good!
迈克∶托尼,你听听,真的是没有试卷,没有考试,或其他别的东西呢.
Mike: Tony, didn't you hear, there's no papers, tests, or anything.
托尼∶恩,为了以防万一,晚点我要查查资料.
Tony: Oh!Just in case I wanna look something up later.
教授∶表演难道仅仅只是要求记住台词,不撞到道具就行了吗?
Professor: So, is acting merely the ability to memorize lines and not
哦,顺便提一下,你们应该要了解这句话是出自谁的口.
bump into the furniture?Oh, by the way, you should all know who said that.
学生:斯潘塞翠西.
Class: Spencer Tracy.
教授∶很好!
Professor: Very good!...
迈克∶你可以借我一张纸和一支笔吗?
Mike: Can I borrow a piece of paper?And a pen.
教授∶那么,到底表演是什么呢?我们在舞台上看见的是表演吗?也许是.那我们在电影中看到的呢?有时是.我们在电视上看到的呢?不能肯定.因此,这个学期我们要从大师那里找到表演的标准,这些大师都是大家耳熟能详的,比如说:奥内尔, Ionescaux,早期的品特,中期的史特林堡,和晚期的易仆生...
Professor: So, what exactly is acting?Is it something you see on a stage?Maybe.Something you see in the cinema?Sometimes.Something you see on television?Doubtful.And so throughout this err...Throughout this semester we will be drawing up standards from the masters.Masters you're all familiar with- O'Neill, Ionescaux, early Pinter, middle Strindberg, late Ibsen...
迈克∶能不能再借我一张纸?我的字写的太大了.最后说的大师的名字叫什么来着?
Mike: Could I borrow another piece of paper? I write kind of big.Who was that last master guy's name?
学生∶易仆生.
Student: Ibsen.
迈克∶谁?
Mike: Who?
Professor: Ibsen.I B S E N.Now, you do know who is, don't you
迈克∶知道,知道.呃,他是比佛利山庄比利中的那个老人,巴迪易仆生!
Mike: Oh sure...err sure...err...He was the old guy in Beverly Hill Billie's, Buddy Ibsen!
教授∶知道了.年轻人,说说你叫什么名字?
Professor: I see.And what is your name young man?
迈克∶啊...迈克西维尔.
Mike: Ahh...Mike Seaver.
教授∶西维尔先生,我认为你可能是以下这三种情况之一,一,你有很多东西要去学,
Professor: Mr.Seaver, you either, A- have a lot to learn,
二,你根本不知道什么时候可以开玩笑,三,或者是以上两种情况都有.
B- don't know when to make a joke, or C- A and B.
迈克∶可以选D吗?
Mike: Is there a D?
教授:我们要得到分数,不是么西维尔先生?
Professor: We'll have to wait until the grades are due, won't we Mr.Seaver?
本:嘿迈克,要不要一起玩投篮?
Ben: Hey Mike, you wanna shoot some hoops?
迈克:不了本.我还要看一晚上书.
Mike: No thanks Benny.I've got a long night of reading ahead of me, alright?
本∶迈克,妈妈和爸爸又不在,你就别再装了.
Ben: Mike, Mom and Dad aren't around.Don't pull this stuff with me.
迈克∶本,听着,开萝尔在楼上房间里吗?
Mike: Benny listen, is Carol up in her room?
本∶是的,她正在为新长的粉刺发愁呢.
Ben: Yes, she's crying about a new zit.
迈克∶哦,好了,我要去找她一趟.
Mike: Oh, well listen, I've got to see her.
本∶特意?
Ben: On purpose?
迈克∶是呀,我需要使用她的词典.
Mike: Yeah, I need to use her dictionary.
本∶花50磅买来的那本?害虫杀手?
Ben: The fifty pound one!The bug killer!
迈克∶是的,本,没错,就是那本.
Mike: Yes.Yeah Benny, that's the one.
本∶蟑螂又来了吗?恩?
Ben: The roaches are back, huh?
迈克∶本,我必须要查几个单词的意思...
Mike: Benny look, I have to look up a few words...err...
呃...嘿...
Hey nothing gets by you, Benny.
这好像和你没关系吧.当然,
You know, if you go upstairs and you ask Carol for that dictionary,
如果你能上楼去找开萝尔把字典拿来,我就让你把比萨饼盒子里的蟑螂都碾碎.
I'll let you squish the ones in the pizza box.
本:成交!开萝尔!
Ben: Deal!Carol!
麦琪∶喂!宝贝儿!
Maggie: Hi, honey!
杰森∶嘿!
Jason: Hey!
麦琪∶你今天晚上会带给我什么惊喜呀?
Maggie: What are you surprising me with tonight?
杰森∶恩,我想等孩子们睡着后,我们也许可以....呃...
Jason: Well ,I thought maybe after the kids went to sleep...maybe we could...err
迈克∶菠菜肉糜!!!!
Mike: Sloppy Joes!!!!
杰森∶嘿迈克!让你兴奋不已的表演课怎么样?
Jason: Hey Mike!How's that acting class you were all excited about?
迈克∶哦,不错,爸爸,真的很好.
Mike: Oh, err, it's great, Dad, just great.
麦琪∶你拿着什么?
Maggie: What are those?
迈克∶书,妈妈.
Mike: They're books, Mom.
杰森∶哦,学校有督促机制吗?
Jason: Yeah, school having a paper drive?
迈克∶没有爸爸,这些是我今晚要看的材料.
Mike: No Dad, this is some stuff that I wanna read tonight.
杰森∶哦!,不错,你现在就在演戏,对吧?
Jason: Oh, that's good, you're acting now, right?
迈克∶拜托,爸爸,
Mike: Look, Dad, is it that unbelievable that I wanna take home a few
难道我自己主动带几千页书回来看看,让你觉得那么难以置信吗?
thousand pages to read for my own amusement?
杰森∶哦,不好意思,迈克,我不知道你是当真的.
Jason: Well, I'm sorry Mike, I didn't know you were so serious.
迈克∶我是认真的,爸爸.
Mike: Well, I am, Dad.You know?I mean look, I may not be as...
你明白,我是说我可能不像开萝尔那样能读那么多书,也不像开萝尔那样爱学习,
as well-read as Carol, I may not be as academically inclined as Carol,
或者,我不像开萝尔那么聪明...
I may not be as smart as Carol...
开萝尔∶只是可能?
Carol: May not be?
麦琪∶开萝尔,现在不是取笑你哥哥的时候.
Maggie: Carol, this is not the time to make fun of your brother.
开萝尔∶啊,我只是就事论事.给你,用完后记得擦掉蟑螂的内脏.
Carol: Ah, I take 'em where I can get 'em.Here, and clean off the roach guts when you're finished.
迈克∶开萝尔,我才不是用它来打臭虫呢.
Mike: Carol, I am not killing bugs, alright?I'm looking up words...big ones!!
我是要查询几个大单词!!很难,
Big, humungous words!Giant words no-one's even heard of;
很难的单词!大家甚至都没有听说过的单词;想弄明白根本不简单.
as hard as that is to comprehend.
麦琪∶啊,我从来没见迈克那样过,是不是出了什么事情,我要去问清楚.
Maggie: Well, I have never seen Mike like that.Whatever's wrong, I can fix it.
杰森∶别去,亲爱的,
Jason: No, honey, wait!He's nineteen years old.
等等!
Come on, you've got to give him a chance to try and work out whatever's
现在是时候给他机会去自己尝试或解决麻烦事了.要对他有信心.
bothering him on his own.Got to have a little faith in him.
麦琪∶杰森,我们说的可是迈克呢.
Maggie: Jason, this is Mike we're talking about.
杰森∶我说过了,要对他有信心.
Jason: I said a little faith.
教授:我的学生们,我相信你今天……
Professor: And so, my fellow actors, I trust you all have audition oppo...
迈克∶对不起我来迟了.
Mike: Sorry I'm late.
教授∶我的学生们,我相信你们今天应该要一起分享试镜机会.
Professor: And so, my fellow actors,
I trust you all have audition opportunities to share with each other this
morning.
凯∶下星期东部村庄剧组要为俄狄浦斯试镜
Kay: The East Village Rep.is holding trials for Oedipus next week.
教授∶哦!对年经演员来说,
Professor: Oh!Wonderful challenge for the young actor.
是个难得的挑战.
And if any of you boys should be lucky enough to get cast in Oedipus,
如果你们中有谁被选中去饰演俄狄浦斯,一定要记得邀请你的妈妈去观看.
don't forget to invite your mother.
托尼∶我也听说他们这个周末在搜湖剧院的通道里为"陨落之后"试镜.
Tony: I heard they're holding auditions for After the Fall,
this weekend at the Soho Theatre, in the alley.
教授∶啊,那是一本不错的剧本;是亚瑟米勒最优秀的一本,西维尔先生你觉得呢?
Professor: Ah.It's a wonderful play; Arthur Miller's best, don't you agree Mr.Seaver?
迈克∶呃...坦白说,我更喜欢推销员之死.
Mike: Err...well actually...errm...I prefer, Death of a Salesman.
教授:我也是.
Professor: Yes, so do I.
迈克∶因为那是我昨天晚上刚刚看过的一本
Mike: Because that's the one I read, last night.
教授∶那,有试镜机会吗?西维尔先生
Professor: So, any more auditions?Mr.Seaver.
迈克∶有,
Mike: Yeah, I read that they're having auditions tomorrow for McGregor's
我看到他们明天要为麦格雷戈的鱼和薯条试镜.
Fish and Chips.
教授∶麦格雷戈的炸鱼?是最新的马尔默特剧本吗?
Professor: McGregor's Fish and Chips?Is that the new Marmot play?
迈克∶噢不;不是的,先生,是他的...呃,
Mike: Oh no, no sir, that's his...err...the old restaurant.
老饭店.你也知道他们的口号的,"我们的鱼一点也不臭!"
You know their slogan, "our fish don't stink!"
教授∶好歹我还知道一点.
Professor: Somehow that one got by me.
迈克∶哦!是的,你看就在这里...
Mike: Oh yeah, well it says right here...err...
呃,戏剧,小黑鱼,快乐的鱼,
Play, Swimmy, the happy fish; twelve commercials, personal appearances,
12小时的广告,个人出镜,还有大笔的钱.
big money.
教授∶电视广告.西维尔先生,
Professor: A television commercial.What will you have for us tomorrow Mr.
那你明天是不是要给我们带点情景喜剧来?
Seaver, something for a sit-com?
迈克∶难道,不需要一个一个来吗?
Mike: But, don't you have to start somewhere?
教授∶就从你开始,西维尔先生.
Professor: Somewhere Mr.Seaver, not nowhere.
学生∶嘿,你去的时候,代我向巴迪问好.
Student: Hey look, when you go, say hi to Buddy Ipsom for me.
教授∶好了,好了!女士们,先生们,玩笑到此结束.让我们做做别的放松训练,好吗?帮我把这个桌子移开,你们分开2组坐.西维尔先生,你不应该在这里.
Professor: Alright, alright!Enough frivolity ladies and gentlemen.Let's loosen up with another exercise, hmm?Move the desk for me please, and I shall want you all in two teams.Mr.Seaver, you shouldn't be here.
迈克∶哦!但是,先生……我是……这个……很抱歉,但是表演是我一直都想要学的.
Mike: Oh, but sir...I'm...this...I'm sorry, but this is what I've always wanted to do.
教授∶不,不,不,
Professor: No, no, no, I mean,
我是说,我要从这里开始展示我们的练习,你要移动一点点.
I'm going to demonstrate the exercise from here.You'll have to move.
迈克∶哦!好的!
Mike: Oh...oh right!
麦琪∶他没有下来吃晚餐,也没有吃甜点,甚至连零食也没有吃.已经27个小时了,我本不想多事,但是,现在我一定要去查个水落石出,到底是什么事情在困扰着我的宝贝儿子.
Maggie: He didn't show up for dinner, dessert, or even a snack.That's it, it's been twenty seven hours, I've been a good sport, but now it's time to find out what's bothering my little boy.
杰森:麦琪!宝贝儿……
Jason: Maggie!Honey...
麦琪∶不要跟我那些我内心深处也懂的大道理!
Maggie: And don't say anything logical or correct that I'll know is right in my heart of hearts!
杰森∶宝贝儿;我只是想说...
Jason: Honey, I was just gonna say...
麦琪∶杰森,有时你让我很吃惊.我们的儿子正在苦闷中,而你呢,却只顾你自己的面子.你要去哪里?
Maggie: Jason, sometimes you amaze me.Our little boy's in agony, and you're about to stuff your face.Where are you going?
杰森∶我给迈克送点零食.
Jason: I'm taking Mike a snack.
麦琪∶你不是说,现在上去是很愚蠢的行为吗?
Maggie: But, you said it was a bad idea to go up there!
杰森∶是,我明白我是自相矛盾,
Jason: Yes I know.I'm inconsistent, Maggie.
麦琪.但是,这件事情引起了我极大的兴趣.
It's part of the wackiness that makes me so damned interesting.
迈克∶(正在读剧本)"当他打算用匕首来自杀的时候,谁都不能阻止他..."嘿,这句话里我只认识一个单词,其他的都要查字典,进来!
Mike: (reading from a play) "When he himself might his quietest make with a bare bodkin, Who would fardols bare..." Hey, there's only one word in this sentence I don't have to look up, Come in!
麦琪∶我们给你拿了点吃的.
Maggie: We brought you something to eat.
迈克∶哦,谢谢.放在那里就好了,我晚一点再吃.
Mike: Oh.Ah...thanks.Just put it down, I'll get to it later.
麦琪∶我们现在该怎么办?
Maggie: What do we do now?
杰森∶麦琪,我已经尽力了……迈克,
Jason: Maggie, I've got us this far, didn't I?
我看你正在学习呀……
So, Mike, you're studying, I see.
迈克∶是.
Mike: Yep.
麦琪∶啊."当他想要用匕首自杀的时候,谁都不能阻止他在疲倦的光线下发出抱怨和流汗."
Maggie: Ahh."When he himself might his quietus make with a bare bodkin.Who would fadols bare, to grunt and sweat under a weary light."
迈克∶哎,我是这个星球上唯一一个不知道哈姆雷特的人吗?如果你问我的话,我只能说麦维尔·杜威中学根本就没有教过这些.
Mike: Hey, am I the only guy in this planet who does not get this Hamlet junk?You know, if you ask me, this does not speak very well of the education I got at Dewey High School!
杰森∶也许他们讲这课的时候,
Jason: Well, maybe you just weren't paying attention the day they covered
你没有用心听.
that.
迈克∶也许,但是,如果是这么重要的课程,
Mike: Well maybe if it was so important they'd cover it for two days.
他们应该讲两天才对呀.如果你们允许的话,
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to get back to some more of this reading,
我又要开始继续读了,就算多读几遍,我还是不会明白的.
that I probably won't understand.
麦琪∶迈克,宝贝儿,
Maggie: Mike, honey, if it'll make you feel better,
如果我说我也不明白什么叫FARDOL的话,会不会让你感觉好点?
I don't have a clue what a fardol is.
迈克∶在我班上的那些家伙,都明白这些.
Mike: Well the kids in my class, do understand this stuff.
你知道吗?有的同学甚至已经演过契诃夫的戏剧了.
You know, and some of 'em have even done plays by Chekhov.
而我呢,
I mean, until two days ago,
在两天以前,还一直以为他是掉下星际旅行的那个俄罗斯人!
I thought Chekhov was the Russian guy off Star trek!
麦琪∶你不可能了解所有的戏剧吧!
Maggie: You can't know every play that's ever been written!
迈克∶妈妈,你跟我讲讲吧.
Mike: Tell me about it, Mom!
我凌晨3点起来,就开始看这些愚蠢的书,
I've been up till three am, reading these stupid things,
但是,我今天在班上出的丑比昨天还大.
and I made a bigger fool out of myself in class today, than I did yesterday.
如果我继续读这些书,他们一定会更加把我当小丑的!
If I keep reading this stuff, they're gonna lynch me!
麦琪∶迈克,你听我说,当你觉得自己是个傻瓜的时候,就证明你实际上不是.很多时候,你爸爸都会觉得他很傻,但是...在课堂上还发生了什么事情?
Maggie: Well Mike, what if you only thought you were making a fool of yourself, and you really weren't.A lot of times, your father thinks he's made a total fool out of himself and err...What else happened in class?
迈克∶还有,今天...我把试镜通知当成了电视广告,那可是真正的工作!麦格雷戈的鱼和薯条.
Mike: Alright, Ok, today...like I brought in this audition for...this audition notice for a television commercial...a real job!McGregor's Fish and Chips.
麦琪∶哦!,我知道他们的广告,"
Maggie: Oh, I know their commercials, "If it smells bad,
如果鱼的味道很难闻,那说明你走错地方了!"
you're in the wrong place!" Or something like that...
迈克∶爸爸,
Mike: Dad, now you see how you and I are staring at Mom,
现在你和我盯着妈妈的神情,就像在笑她不在状态一样;今天,
like she's out of her mind;
全班同学也是这样看着我的!!
well that is how the whole class stared at me today!!
杰森∶好了...
Jason: Well...
迈克∶你明白吗?我根本不懂!
Mike: You know I...I just don't get it!I don't get it!
根本就不懂!
You know, I feel like I don't fit in.
我觉得我与他们格格不入.
And I have always been able to fit in with everybody!
以前我可以跟每个人都相处的很好的!在麦维尔·杜威四年的时间里,
And at Dewey, even though Principal Dewitt would...
虽然杜维浩校长几乎每天都要惩罚我,但是我知道在他的内心深处,
would punish me for four years every single day, I know that deep down,
他是爱我的!
the man liked me!
杰森∶他不喜欢你.
Jason: He loathed you.
麦琪∶他喜欢.
Maggie: He did.
迈克∶在我班上的那些家伙都知道的比我多,
Mike: Well, it's just that the kids in my class know more,
并且他们已经参加过的演出可能比我一辈子要参加的演出都还要多.
and have done more than I ever will.
我觉得自己只不过是自己开了个想学表演的的玩笑.
you know, I think I'm just kidding myself about this whole acting thing.
杰森∶那,你接下来要做什么呢?
Jason: So, what are you gonna do about it?
迈克∶我也不知道.正想问你呢.
Mike: I don't know.I'm supposed to ask you that.
杰森∶迈克,我们不能回答你这个问题.
Jason: Well, we can't answer that, Mike.
麦琪∶杰森,你就会为自己辩护.
Maggie: Well, speak for yourself, Jason.
杰森:不,不是,宝贝儿.
Jason: No, honey, he's not a little boy.He's got to make his own decisions.
他现在已经不是小孩子了,应该要学会自己做决定了.
I think, Mike, that this is your dream and only you can decide if the
迈克,我觉得这是你的梦想,只有你自己才能决定所受的痛苦是否值得.
pain is worth it.
迈克∶那,值得吗?
Mike: So, is it worth it?
麦琪∶迈克,现在你要自己考虑清楚了.恩,
Maggie: Mike, you're gonna have to figure this out on your own.
我也很善变.我们出去吧,出去吧.
Well, I can be wacky, too.Come on, let's go, let's go.
迈克∶哦,我看到哪里了?哦,对,我正在查"匕首".
Mike: Oh, where was I?Oh yeah, I was looking up, "bodkin".
(迈克正在复习他之前的表演)
(Mike looking back at some acting he did before)
迈克∶如果我确实进步并且发生了很大的改变,你会...
Mike: "If I do improve and make a big change, would you be...
我是说,你能不能..
I mean, could you be...
学生∶"我是呀,我一直都是."
Student: "I am now.I always have been."
迈克∶"我猜这是我们之间最重要的一次交谈了."
Mike: "So, I guess this is a pretty important talk we've been having."
学生∶对.
Student: "Yes...yes"
迈克∶是.
Mike: Yeah.
迈克∶虽然这不是俄狄浦斯,不是哈姆雷特,
Mike: OK.This isn't Oedipus, this isn't Hamlet,
也不是推销员之死,但是,
it's not even death of a Salesman, but it's a start, it's not nowhere,
这是一个开始,至少我也参加过试镜了,今天,
it is somewhere, and I am not too good to make my start right here...today...
此时此刻,就是我的起点.
now!
试镜员∶鱼还是薯条?
Auditioner: Fish or chip?
迈克∶什么?
Mike: What?
试镜员∶我问你是想演鱼还是薯片?
Auditioner: What are you auditioning for, fish or chip?
迈克∶哦,呃,演薯片的话会有个人镜头吗?
Mike: Oh, well...err...Are chips making personal appearances?
试镜员∶谁会注意一跟薯条呀?他们只想看小黑鱼,
Auditioner: Who'd come out to see a chip, huh?
快乐的鱼.
They wanna see Swimmy, the happy fish.
迈克∶哦!哦!那好吧,我就演小黑鱼.
Mike: Oh, oh, alright, well Swimmy it is.
试镜员∶很棒的选择.请坐.掰一片鱼翅.
Auditioner: Excellent choice.Have a seat.Break a fin.
迈克∶请问这里有人坐吗?
Mike: Ah, is this seat taken?
男人∶坐!坐!
Man: Sit!Sit!So,
我试过镜的朋友跟我讲过他们的过程.他们会让你戴上鱼翅和鱼鳃,
my friend auditioned for this a little earlier and told me all about it.
然后趴在地上咧开嘴笑,
They make you wear fins and gills and lie on your stomach and grin like
在你的嘴里放个鱼钩,然后,
crazy, with a hook in your mouth,
所有的薯条就开始唱,"我们的鱼一点也不臭!"
while all the chips sing, "our fish don't stink!"
迈克∶啊,不过没有关系...呃...他们让我怎么做都行,因为经历过这个星期的难堪后,这些对我来说,已经没什么大不了的了.
Mike: Ah, well...err...hey, whatever they make me do is fine, 'cause after the way I've been humiliated this week, it doesn't matter.
男人∶哇,你结婚了?看看那个鱼上的鳃!
Man: Wow, so you're married.Wow, look at the gills on that one!
迈克∶嗨!等等!我认识他们.
Mike: Hey, wait a minute, I know them.What the heck are they doing here?
他们在这里干嘛?他们不是都在参加戏剧的演出和夏季剧集的演出吗?那时我跟他们说这里有试镜的时候,
I mean, they've been in plays and summer stock,
他们还都笑话过我呢.恩,
and they laughed at me when I told 'em about this audition.
他们并不比我优秀.嗨,我真是个木头人!
I mean they're no better than I am.Hey, have I been a chump!
试镜员∶注意啦!要开始拍摄小黑鱼的镜头了.
Auditioner: Come on people!The part of Swimmy has already been cast.
演员们∶嘿!什么!
Actors: Hey!What!
男人∶嗨,我已经连续吃了3天的虫子了!
Man: Hey, I've been eating worms for three days!
教授∶先生.再来一次,
Professor: Once again gentlemen, very clever material!
很聪明的材料!希望我的小黑鱼能够进入你的视线.
Just hope my swimming lives up to your vision.
托尼∶你相信那个骗子!!
Tony: Do you believe that guy, what a phony!!
凯:他可不是看上去的样子.
Kay: He's not what he seemed at all, m Apparently not a lot of people are.
托尼∶迈克?
Tony: Mike?
迈克∶啊……让我们重新认识一下吧.我是迈克西维尔,我长这么大,在高中的时候演过两不戏.
Mike: Ah...why don't we just start over.My names Mike Seaver, I've done two plays in my whole life, both of them at high school.
托尼∶托尼dissipio,并且我有做夏季剧集.我负责布景.
Tony: Tony Dissipio, and I have done summer stock.I built scenery.
凯∶凯特麦克旦尼尔,我并不习惯真实的演出,因为这样很费时间.我想要表演.
Kay: Kate McDonnell, and I'm not used to this honesty stuff, it's gonna take a while.I wanna act.
托尼∶我也是.
Tony: Me too.
迈克∶我也是.
Mike: Me too.
男人∶嗨,
Man: Hey, I just called my service;
我刚才给服务台打电话了;据说纽约动物园正在找长的像海象的人.我觉得自己不适合,
New York Zoo is looking for people that look like walruses.
但是我认为你可以去!!
It's not right for me, but I figured I'd toss it your way!!
杰森∶做了早餐.
Jason: Make breakfast.
麦琪∶煮了咖啡.
Maggie: Make coffee.
迈克∶呵呵,不必担心,我不是刚从外面回来,行不?
Mike: Oh, you guys, don't worry, I'm not just getting home, OK?
杰森∶不必担心;我们信任你.
Jason: Don't worry, we believe you.
麦琪∶恩,我只是很欣慰,
Maggie: Yeah.I'm just thrilled that you're excited about your class...
你开始重视所有的课程了.
any class.
迈克∶呵呵,你说对了.
Mike: Hey, you bet, and you know, thanks and...
不过我还是要谢谢你们,给我机会自己做决定,这些经历真的让我的生活发生了变化.
You guys letting me make that decision on my own, it's really changed my life.
麦琪∶迈克,我想我们现在终于可以说对你是完全信任的了.
Maggie: Well Mike, I guess we can finally say that we trust you.
迈克∶哦!谢谢妈妈.
Mike: Oh, well thanks, Mom.
女孩1∶迈克!!!我们还在等你的咖啡呢.
Girl: Mike!!!We're still waiting for the coffee.
迈克∶来了,来了,再等一分钟.
Mike: Oh...err...just one minute.
杰森∶再等一秒钟!
Jason: Just one second!
女孩2∶我现在可以出来了吗?
Girl 2: Can I come out now?
迈克∶哦!出来吧!哦,让我来帮你.
Mike: Oh, there you are!Oh, hey, let me help you out.
好了,就在这里吧,我马上就上来了.
Here, come on out here.I'll be right up, OK?
麦琪∶迈克……
Maggie: Look, Mike...
迈克∶妈妈,爸爸,听我说,你知道吗?如果你们没有让我自己拿主意的话,在这样的情况下我可能觉得有必要跟你们解释,可是,现在我不必了.
Mike: Mom, Dad, listen, you know if I weren't in that stage in life where you trusted me and wanted me to make my own decisions, I would feel the need to explain here...but I don't.
杰森∶嘿!站住!
Jason: Hey, hold on!
麦琪∶你认为你可以在没有……把她带出去吗?
迈克∶知道了!
00:21:36,100
Maggie: Do you think you can walk out of her without.. Mike: Got ya!